whether you're a rookie or a vet a
barbell is arguably the most versatile
strength building tool that you could
have in your home gym now similar to all
gym equipment you need to be methodical
when searching for the best option for
you specifically so that's what I'm here
to do today whether you're looking for a
rock solid power bar a barbell to help
you with your Olympic lifts or simply
one bar to help you crush it all with I
got you
[Music]
covered
what's up y'all it's Jake back in my
home away from home that's right the
barbin garage gym and for those who
don't know I've spent a lot of time over
the past year reviewing a lot of
barbells so today it's time for me to
tell you my top picks on the market and
since you know this is a long video and
I want to make the absolute most of my
time why don't I go ahead and tell y'all
my top pick overall drum roll
please it's the living fit barbell now
that might be a bit of a surprise for
some people but when you really think
about the price tag the versatility and
the coding options this bar is just
honestly really tough to top now I'm
going to expand on why this barbell is
ranked our number one option but we have
a whole lot of other categories to talk
about today too such as best on a budget
best for CrossFit and like I said a
whole lot more but before I do all of
that I got to let y'all know that we
have a full written article that details
all the information I'm going to be
talking about today and I think you're
going to find it really helpful so all
you got to do is search barbend best
barbells everything's going to pull up
right there for you and you can just
read into more detail why we chose each
individual
[Music]
bar okay so I know I just spoiled the
fun for y'all and told you the top pick
it's the living fit Barb well but let's
expand on that and so for me the main
two things here are the versatility
because this is a multi-purpose bar but
also the really affordable price tag I
mean this bar just checks off both of
those boxes and that's important because
you know a lot of people really
emphasize both of those factors whenever
they're you know building out a home gym
and really just looking for one barbell
to serve you know across all their lifts
in general all right so you can load up
to 1,500 lb on this bar and it has a
solid tinsil strength rating of 200,000
PSI
but the volcano style knurling right
here is really grippy you know it's not
going to tear up your hands as you go to
do an Olympic lift it's also you know
good it gives you a you know really nice
grip sorry it gives you a really nice
grip whenever you're going to do your
power lifts okay so I really like how
there's bronze bushings but also
bearings in the loading sleeve so it
gives you that really solid spin rate
which definitely comes in handy as you
go to you turn the bar and get under it
you know during your Olympic movements
okay now there's also two different
coating options right here which is you
know a really sweet thing too so I've
got the Chrome version and there's a
sakote version as well but really cherry
on top as I mentioned it's the price tag
all right so this chrome one's going to
cost you 200 bucks while that sakote
version is 225 now it's not a rarity to
find a barbell around that price tag but
it is a rarity to find one for that
price that performs as well as this bar
does right here so there it is laid out
nice and and pretty for you our top pick
for the best bar on the market it's the
living fit
[Music]
barbell okay so this next barbell on our
list came in a very close second place
and we're talking about the rep Fitness
Colorado bar all right now it came in
second place but it also is our choice
for the best barbell for weight lifting
and for those who don't know what I'm
talking about I'm talking about Olympic
lifting through power cleans hang cleans
clean and jerk SN snatch all that stuff
but let's talk about you know why it
came you know in second place our runner
up so it's also a multi-purpose bar you
have a really solid volcano style
knurling got the Dual neural markings
it's got a two actually 190,000 ensil
strength rating it also comes in Chrome
or cako I got the Chrome right here in
front of me I really like how you have
composite bushings in the loading
sleeves it's quieter overall it's
probably going to last you longer than
bronze bushings will but main reason it
came in second place it's cuz it's more
expensive than the living fit bar bill
is all right so it comes in two
different options 15 and 20 kg so the 15
kg version in Chrome is going to run you
around 270 while the cerakote version is
going to be about 280 now with the 20
kgam version that's going to be 320 and
330 so honestly since you have to spend
more money on it that's pretty much why
it came in second place now when it
comes to your weightlifting well that's
because it meets you know the iwf specs
so so it's got 282 mm diameter I once
again I really like these composite
bushings right here it gives you a
really solid spin rate and allows you to
really get underneath that bar and it
reduces the torque on your elbows and
your wrists now these composite bushings
also have a little bit of a noise
dampening effect and that's really nice
you know you're repeatedly dropping that
barbell so it's going to be a little bit
more of a dull sound which is nice if
you have neighbors nearby also you know
this 190k tinsil string rating know it's
still strong enough to handle your lifts
but you know it's going to have a little
bit more whip which is something that
you definitely want so whips basically
you know flexion with the bar so
basically you know that's why it is our
pick for the best weightlifting bar so
there it is runner up best weightlifting
bar rep Fitness Colorado
[Music]
bar
okay so now it's time for the new kit on
the Block we're going to talk about the
iron bull competition bar which also
cracked our best list in two different
spots best for a budget and best for
beginners so my people who are Balling
on a budget don't want to spend $500 on
a barbell or even 320 you know like with
the rep Colorado bar this is a really
solid option for you to consider so it's
available in 15 and 20 kg comes in Black
zinc black chrome and stainless steel so
there's different options for you right
there but you're not going to spend more
than $300 so this ranges from 200 to 300
$300 for stainless steel is unheard of
and is quite frankly a a steel now you
know if you're a beginner you know you
arguably you know you don't want to
spend a whole lot of money on a barbell
right so that's kind of why these go
hand inand right here also if you're a
beginner you likely are still learning
you know your specific style of lift you
want to do and this is a a multi-purpose
bar so it can handle everything and also
beginners typically don't have you know
a whole lot of calluses built up on
their hands and if you start using a
barbell that's too sharp it's going to
rip your hands up so this barbell is a
little bit more on the passive side and
I think it's going to be really nice for
anybody who's you know just now learning
you know the proper technique and and
really just getting into the fitness
life so there it is folks ironbow
competition bar best for my friends
Balling on a budget and best for those
beginn
all right now enough with some
multi-purpose bars what about some
classic powerlifting and if you're
looking to dominate The Big Three which
is squat bench and deadlift look no
further than rep fitnesses Flagship
power bar that's right I'm talking about
the Double Black Diamond all right so
the nerling right here is a sharp
Mountain nerling it's inspired by you
know the most difficult and steep
Terrain in the Rockies it also has a
tensil strength rating of 200,000 PSI
which is plenty strong it's also going
to allow the bar to be stiff and you
want that when you're going to do your
power lifts so that's really the main
reason here but also the money all right
so it comes in Chrome cak Co and
stainless steel now that stainless steel
gets pretty expensive it's around 450
bucks but that's fully you know in to
end stainless steel now this Saker right
here it's right around 330 bucks so it's
cheap than some other competitors like
the Rogue Ohio power bar so honestly
y'all the way it's performed this is my
baby my power lifts I think this is
easily the best power bar on the market
but I mentioned it's stiff and since
this is a stiff barbell I love using it
for squats so you know what that means
it's also our top barbell for squatting
all right so aside from a duffalo bar
which has you know a curved shape and a
tsunami bar you know that bends like
Gumby you don't want your barbell to be
bending under heavy loads as you're
squatting and that's something you just
simply don't have to worry about here
and then also you know you do have you
know the center knurling right here and
it's sharp as attack so it's going to
stay nice and secure on your back so
that's it folks best for powerlifting
best for squatting none other than the
rep Fitness Double Black
Diamond hold me down I'm too this is my
time ready to shine brighter than all
okay so we just talked about some
powerlifting we already talked about
some weightlifting what about CrossFit
well for us we had to go with the again
faster Pursuit Olympic Bar yes I know it
says Olympic Bar but it's actually also
a multi-purpose bar so you have
self-lubricating bronze bushings in the
loading sleeves which is really nice you
don't have to worry about lubricating
them over time the nerling here y'all it
is super grippy I'm talking about super
duper grippy I know those really goofy
but hey it gets the point across you
know this volcano style nerling it's cut
deeper than some other bars on this list
it's not going to tear you up but it is
just sweet really gets the job done you
also have a tinsil strength rating of
190,000 PSI and it comes in this pretty
sweet and Shiny Bright zinc finish now
comes in 15 kg and 20 kg now this is why
we ranked it partly while we ranked it
as the best barbell for women cuz it is
available in 15 kg that 15 kg version is
going to run you right around 270 while
this 20 kg version is about 285 so
honestly it's a pretty good deal too
with that approachable price TX there it
is best for CrossFit best for women the
again faster Pursuit
barbell
sing all right now when it comes to
deadlifting you definitely want to
Target a barbell it's going to allow you
to achieve the best grip possible you
don't ever want to be limited by your
grip so for this category we're rocking
with the bells of Steel bare naked
powerlifting bar 2.0 the nuring here is
sharp as a tack Sharp As a Razor it's a
cheese grater whatever you want to call
it I mean it is super sharp and that's
because it is bare steel so if you don't
already know barbells with a coating are
pretty notorious for being a little
slippery and that's something you don't
want in general but you know especially
while deadlifting right you don't want
that to slip out of your hands and
that's something that you're not going
to have to worry about here I really
don't think you have to worry about that
at all I mean this nerling is so sharp
that it will leave indentions on your
hands now that might be too sharp for
some people but I personally like it now
bar is only 220 bucks as well so when it
comes to you know technically you know a
specialty bar it's a pretty sweet deal
remember though bare steel offers
virtually zero protection from rusting
corrosion I got a little bit built up
right here after a few months and that's
just something that it's on me I need to
clean it something that you need to do
every once in a while and when I say
that I mean once or twice a month just
to make sure it's staying in that
pristine condition but end of the day
you know this bare steel grip is really
tough to beat and so when it comes to
deadlifting this is our top
[Music]
pit okay so since we just on the topic
of deadlifting I figured I'd go ahead
and bust out the rep Fitness open trap
bar which is my favorite trap bar on the
market so don't know trap bars are an
excellent tool when it comes to
deadlifting because it allows you to
lift in a more natural way with your
body you know your handles are right
here on either side of your shoulders as
opposed to holding a heavy barbell out
in front of you so if you're new to
deadlifting maybe you have an injury
you're
rehabbing trap bar deadlifts are an
excellent excellent tool for you to use
honestly it's just great overall it's
going to put less stress on your body
now this is not the open trap only open
trap bar on the market but I think it's
one of the better values due to the
overall high quality but it's also 400
bucks now it's a lot for just you look
at it on paper you know $400 for one bar
it's kind of a lot you know especially
for a trap bar but these other open trap
bars that this one is competing with
like I said this is one of the better
values now I really like how you know
you have two different handles that's
not a rarity but I still like that the
one up top is going to be great for
anybody who is you know like I said
learning and then you can increase your
range of motion by going after the
bottom one right here there's also
multiple handles that you can purchase
so they're standard wide narrow and
there's some rotating ones as well and
you know that's going to allow you to
you know choose the one that's best
suited for your body type also speaking
of the handles they're 28 mm in diameter
so it's you know right there with the
barbell and they have this pretty
aggressive Mountain style knurling so
it's you know going to give you a really
solid grip as you go to do those
deadlifts this is also really versatile
yes you know you got the open design
right here actually and that's thanks
because of this built-in Jack and it
makes loading and unloading your weight
plates a breeze it's so easy for you to
do but you know this open design is also
going to allow you to do additional
workouts you know specifically stuff
like Bulgarian split squats just cuz you
know not trapped you know within it but
this is also a rackable trap bar so if
you have a power rack at home you can
toss it up in your your J Hooks right
there and you can squat with it it's
that's actually you know I've been
pretty successful with that you can also
try to bench press with it if you want
to and since the loading sleeves are you
know the same length as an actual
barbell you're going to be able to load
up a good amount of weight with it as
well so here it is right in front of you
lo and behold the best trap bar on on
the market the rep Fitness open trap
[Music]
bar now Amazon's arguably the best place
to buy anything right so why not talk
about the best barbell on Amazon now I
don't have it in front of me but for
this award we went with the Synergy
games serot barbell this barbell has
190k tensil strength rating it's got
five needle bearings in each loading
sleeve so you're going to get a really
solid rate of Spin and it's not going to
cost you more than 230 bucks whether you
go for the 15 or 20 kgr version now
because the nerling is pretty passive
it's going to be best suited for Olympic
and you know CrossFit style lifts but
we've been pretty high on this barbell
for a while so it's definitely one that
you should check out now when it comes
to the best standard barbell we landed
on the sporzon standard weightlifting
bar now once again I don't have it out
here in front of me but we've also been
pretty high on this barbell for a while
so for anybody who doesn't know what a
standard barbell is instead of meeting
specific requirements set by the iwf or
ipf International powerlifting
International weightlifting federations
standard barbells vary in terms of their
diameter length weight capacity weight
all of that okay so with this specific
bar you can choose for it to be 5 six or
7 ft long and it has a 700 lb weight
capacity which is you know
significantly weaker less whatever you
want to call it than you know the
standard 1500 lb capacity all these
other bars have had now this bar still
has a 28 mm diameter which is nice you
know it's going to be a nice you know
introductory bar it's great for
beginners you know this is a really
solid option CU you know all these other
bars are around 28 282 you whatever it
is it's also only going to cost you $70
so you know if like I said if you're a
beginner you're kind of testing the
waters of fitness and and learning more
about it I think it's a pretty solid
option worth considering all right so
there it is folks our list of the best
barbells on the market now there might
be a few questions you're asking first
of all you know how did you come up with
this list and why isn't a barbell from a
company like AO on here well we really
you know are factoring in money first of
all you know you of course a $1,000
barbell is probably going to out compete
some of these bars but that's not very
practical
not very many people have the budget to
go and spend $11,000 or more on just a
barbell so I don't want to lead you down
that direction all right now we also
really wanted to factor in actual
functionality of each individual barbell
all right so if a barbell is listed as
an Olympic Bar but doesn't have a quick
spin rate and ensil strength isn't very
good and you know the whip isn't very
good either well then it just simply
doesn't belong for that category and
then we we also wanted to factor in the
durability so the tensil strength you
know the Finish whether it has one or
not and then the sleeve construction so
whether it's needle bearings ball
bearings or bronze bushings maybe even
you know composite bushings there it is
folks the method to our Madness on how
we landed on the top barbells on the
market now one more question you might
ask is which one do I buy you know which
one should I go for well you know
obviously there's specific bars that are
meant for specific style of lifts and
you know if you're trying to focus on
those lifts then you should go and get
the best barbell that matches up with
that lift wow said that lift a lot right
there didn't I now another thing here is
that you got to factor in you know your
actual environment right so you know if
you're somebody you know stashing all
your gear in a really humid garage or
you don't have climate control right
then you're definitely going to want to
Target a barbell that's either cak Co or
stainless steel that's my opinion you
know that way you're getting the highest
level of protection protection from rust
and corrosion also you need to factor in
you know the the grip you're going to
get from the nerling there there's a few
factors in there but bottom line as long
as you align your budget with your goals
you can't go wrong with any of these bar
[Music]
bills all right well that's a wrap on
today's video over the best barbells on
the Market we're really high on All
These Bars and I'm confident that each
and every single one of them will serve
you really well thanks for hanging out
with me y' all I hope this video was
really helpful and that I was able to
detail every single one of these options
in full as always say posted for my next
video but remember we have a full
written article that pairs with this
video and you definitely should check it
out all you got to do is search barbend
best barbells it's going to pull right
up for you I'll catch youall next
time
[Applause]
[Music]
hey